Actually first point we have a website now
You can find a website
if you go to the repository on my github that you can click there on the link and you get
Redirected to the website where you have the summaries of the previous class and the previous lab, right?
So it's your duty to go over those
summaries before class
otherwise if I take the first 15 minutes
Revising what we have seen last time then we have 15 minutes less to see new stuff, right?
It's very hard when we have just 50 minutes on Tuesday
Nevertheless we start with a question. So let's say I'd like to do classification between images of dogs and cats
If this is my cat image, where will be my dog image?
Near to this point, right? So, how can we tell them apart?
first of all, I had to take it if this is the zero I will have to
Talk to suppose the talk. What am I doing here in my translation? How do you translate stuff?
Matrix multiplication
Okay, what does matrix multiplication do
Rotation reflection
Scaling and shear right shear what it is pronounced actually scaling
How can you do scaling? also
why are scalars called scalars?
do because they
Scale yeah good
Right, right, so you can always think about a matrix. You can just normalize it such that you have like unitary
determinant and then you actually have a scalar which is changing the
You know the size right
so you can have I usually think about matrices as rotation
And so I usually just say we rotate stuff in whatever dimensional space
And then we are going to be doing another operation with neural nets which is gonna be squashing
So you're going to be me repeating these very many times
Neural nets are simply rotation and squashing rotation and squashing was coming after
rotation and then
Fantastic. All right. So let's get starting. I started then, you know just because I like advertising
I just put there my handle
And again, if you need to say anything just call me ALF have no idea what's going on
Please repeat and if you don't know who that guy is you may have a look about TV series from the nineties
anyhow, Oh a double n
What is it?
Artificial neural networks, I guess. Yeah
supervised learning
Classification so there's gonna be kind of a revised of stuff
He has already seen before but you know in a very much prettier way because I spent the whole day making this stuff for you
All right
so let's go on and we have this guy right we have seen this last time and let's say those are
simply three branches of a spiral
So my case in this case, what is where is gonna be my data living?
On so, where is the data here if I show you this stuff here?
[Audience: branches]
Those branches are made of points and these points live on what space
R2 right is the plane. So all those points are moving around that plane. Why did I show colors?
Those are the labels, right so 3 different classes, 3 different labels
You can make this drawing with matplotlib and Python and numpy. Okay
on the other side
oh, yeah, so we have like a T goes from 0 to 1 and then C is gonna be the class from 1 to
capital C in this case
Let's make things a little bit more spicy. So let's add some
Crap there such that we have more
Crappy looking data, that is like actually more really sorry
Okay
What does classification?
Mean if you'd like to do craft classification, let's use the you know, whatever thing you want what's called?
The thing that no regression logistic regression, so what does logistic regression do here in this case
So it's going to do something like this right some linear planes for separating the data. What's the main issue here?
Second
[Audience]
It's not linearly separable, so but what is the main issue here? How what how would you define was the issue here?
Like yes, they are not linearly separable therefore
you have
[Audience]
Yeah, but what doesn't what don't you like from that drawing
Right, so points in one region you have multiple classes, right?
This means that those branches are crossing my decision boundaries, which are linear
Huh? So, how can we fix that?
[Audience]
Okay, because it will be seen my
Video from from last week. So usually how people saying oh just you know
Like make those decision boundary non linear, right? That's what use or the other professors do
I do only cool the things that are more cool. So I just get the data to be linearly separable, right?
That was just different perspective to see the same stuff
Anyhow, the main issue here is that we have intersection between these decision boundaries and data and therefore
I'm gonna try to do this right and you already seen the video from last time. So, okay. This is no news or
the thing that you may be more useful
See how the decision boundary is over training will try to adapt. What is the you know?
Like the the distribution of this data here. We are watching things from the bottom up
so if you have your network where the first layer is on the bottom and the last layer is on the top and if you
Draw networks in the other direction you get one grade less. So the input is gonna be on the
Bottom why is that?
Why do we have input on the bottom does anyone can anyone guess?
Yeah, well their neural network
[Audience]
Aha, that's correct, right
So we have low level features at the lower part of the network
And as you climb up in the hierarchy, you basically want to draw this network in this the way it is made, right?
So you have high in the hierarchy in the upper part
So if you put some classifier you will put a classifier on top, right?
so if you the first time I was reading a paper now from
Geoffrey he's blah blah. I put a classifier on top of
of the network I'm thinking. What's the top of a network? I have no idea, right?
So networks are drawn from bottom to top with the first layer on the bottom where you have the input coming in
Lower level features is you climb up you have the top and therefore if you have multiple outputs, it's called a multi-headed network
Right like a hydra, whatever. It's called
Anyhow, so we're gonna figure out now in this lesson how we can do these things. Do you know how to do this stuff?
No, yes, okay you should be because you should have taken machine learning before
But perhaps is not linearly separable, right? So we just add one more layer and things start working. Anyhow
Training data. Okay. So yes yesterday
Well last week we have seen that a neural network when you just initialize it, it makes some kind of transformation
So we are feeding that kind of cloud the walls. It was which was sample from a Gaussian distribution with a
Identity matrix as covariance matrix and mean zero. So what was the roughly?
average radius of that cloud of points
[Audience: 3]
3 you actually remember very good
The radius was 3 right so things were within a radius of 3 and those kind of circular shape
It was feed inside the network and the network was
Getting you any kind of arbitrary transformation, which was super pretty right?
Yes, it was very pretty. Yeah good
but then the transformation wasn't
Instrumental to do anything right? So today we're gonna see how by using data we can enforce
Some kind of meaning over that kind of transformation that a network does by itself
And so data is going to be the most important part. So here we're gonna have
That should be in pink
Yes, it's too bright in here. So whatever. So the X is going to be my input data
It's bold because represents a vector and this guy lives in our end. Okay, how much is n in our case?
Two because
[Audience]
Because points live on that space right? Hope the spires
Okay, fantastic, and then it's gonna be my ice sample. I have several samples, right and this takes quite long to draw
you have several samples and they're like
Row vectors and I put them I stack them one on top of each other and I have M of them
Right, so that matrix. What what is the size of this matrix?
Shout louder n by m fantastic, so I have "n" columns and "m" in the height
if I would use these metrics for doing some operations, what is the dimension where I'm shooting to
Try again
"m" And okay
because the height of the matrix is gonna be the dimension where you shoot to and then wait for the domain the metrics in a
Bigger dimension where you shoot from right because you multiply you know row times columns. right?
All right, cool
Sorry, we have Ci which is going to be my different classes for each of those
points in the 2d plane
And so here we're gonna have those Ci 's gonna be equal to 1 to capital K before it was capital C
I see how to fix that. I know
So how many how much is capital K here?
3 because we
Have seen 3 colors. Yeah, fantastic. All right. So if I stack all the Cᵢ how many Cᵢ do I have?
Second, M.
So you should stack M of these guys you get a
Likely a column vector here C
Alright, finally, this is a height of M
But the problem with this kind of notation like 1 2 3, whatever
Basically is that they introduced some kind of ordering right? So class 1 comes before class 2 which comes before just 3 and
It doesn't make any sense, right? They are colors. So it's a categorical distribution
I don't want to have something that also has order therefore. I'm gonna be using this alternative
representation which I'm gonna be basically converting those T's into vectors of the size of my capital K
so the number of classes and then I'm gonna have a 1 in correspondence of the class, which is indexed by the
See the specific Ci, ok?
So let's say Ci is gonna be equal 1 that you have basically the first guy here
Ok, and since we are talking about mathematics I can count from 1
right 1 2 3 if you are talking about Python and
C++ whatever so you switch gear you have different hot., you can count from 0, Math you count from 1
So if you stack all those Ci's converted into that representation what you get
We don't have numbers just use letters
You have M by K matrix, right
So this is going to be my capital Y matrix and then you have my capital K number of columns and M
Number of rows and each of these guys here is going to be a vector
which is ᴷ where only one
item is set to one and so you can say that the zero norm is equal to one
Moreover you can also think about this notation has having sound probability math
Which is completely
Concentrated in one specific spot right? So you have three possible spots. You have three possible classes you put all your
100% bet over that specific category
The network will try to approximate this I won't be able to but that's how we train a network with these kind of hard labels
questions so far
Sorry that was exercise questions so far am I too slow?
Yes a little bit. No, okay
Do you like the font the colors? Okay. Thank you
It takes forever
All right latex
That's why we moved to markdown, right?
All right. Anyhow, so this will be basically the first exercise you have something similar in your first homework
So we skip this because it's gonna be due for two weeks
And basically if this would have been a tutorial it would have been typing stuff now
All right
so
Let's see how a fully networked fully connected network works and look like so at the bottom Y is at the bottom
Say again
The input is at the bottom Y
Lower-level feature fantastic. What's the color of the X?
Pink, I mean, yes, that's correct. But yeah
Then we get a fine transformation is shown there by the arrow and then we get into that
Green F where F is gonna be a non-linearity
The output of the F is going to be called H H which is representing my hidden layer, okay
So H is something that is inside a network and I can't see from outside. And so it's called hidden
It's bold because it's a vector
Moreover then I have another affine transformation
You only see the matrix there which maps to G which is another nonlinear transformation
And now you have the final output which is ŷ
And so the output color is it don't say white, but what's the bubble output bubble color?
Blue right and then the hidden is gonna be green. It's gonna be always constant. All right, so these are the only questions
Basically, you're gonna see in in this course
You have the hidden layer H vector is gonna be it is nonlinear
Function point-wise nonlinear function which is so element-wise nonlinear function of a fine transformation of the input
Which is the X?
here
Plus, you know the bias, right? So this is a linear operator plus the bias
This is a fine transformation. And then the F is gonna be your nonlinear mapping
Again, then you have your ŷ which is gonna be my output of the network
My hypothesis is gonna be a nonlinear function
I'll apply to each element of this vector here and this vector is basically a affine
Transformation of the hidden layer. Okay, that's all you get in a neural network
Affine transformation. I usually call them rotations
I called nonlinear function as squashing and so you just repeat rotation squashing rotation squashing rotation squashing
Fantastic, thank you. All right, so that's it right easy, right so far know you have a question Mike interphase ask
What's up?
[Audience]
Yeah, both F and G are arbitrary nonlinear functions you can use anything you like
This is only one hidden layer my output layer is gonna be my blue guy. Let's add the output
You can see ŷ on top
So if output and the X is going to be your input on the bottom
So I call this one 3 layer neural network Yann looks like he's calling this 2 layer network
I call it free day on your network because there is a input neuron at the bottom
There is a hidden neuron at the center and it is an output. So 1 2 3, but he counts from zero like
Programmers so 2 layer, but no see how many affine transformation does a 3 layer neural network have?
[Audience: 2]
Fantastic how many layers of neurons you have?
3 okay, cool. Yeah question
[Audience]
Aha, yeah, well fine transformation right so there is also translation
Because I liked usually to extract the scaling and scaler from the matrix and then I have my unitary
determinant matrix, which is basically
Rotating stuff and then you had the other one which is scaling
They also have flipping right for if you have the determinant, which is negative, right?
Usually matrix is just rotating stuff. It's a bit hard to think about in high dimensions
I just say matrices rotate stuff because they apply the same kind of movement of everything right so it's kind of
global operation
Other questions
All right, so
Example of nonlinear functions are here a few. So the first one is positive part
basically, you get the positive as it is if it's negative you set it to 0 other people call it ReLU, rectified linear unit, or
Other stuff I don't know
Yeah, whatever. I like positive part, which is math ish. Then there is a sigmoid which is 1/(1+ e⁻ˣ) whatever x.
Hyperbolic tangent which is just a rescale version of this sigmoid
We saw that last time then there is the soft arg max
You're going to call it this way
Because it's going to be just a softer version of a arg max, an arg max is going to give you all zeros
but an index equal to 1 in correspondence of the
correct highest value its soft max
It's gonna give you something like that where it's gonna be almost 1 on the highest value kind of 0 ish everywhere else
Right, but if you have 2 guys at the same height
You're gonna get half and half and the rest is going to be kind of 0. Okay. Yeah
[Audience]
AAAAH
Guess this is a nice derivative
This guy is easy to I think used for training I think you could use
That kind of normalization span
So the question was like why don't we use a like?
Resizing like why don't you?
Automatically
you know set the output to be within a
0 to 1 range
I guess because it's gonna be dependent on the output right, you change the output you have to change all the time
With scaling. This one is just one scaling all the ways the same I guess. Yeah, that could be the answer
all right, so
Uh-huh. Okay, and this took five hours drawing. Okay. We have our X on the left-hand side with five elements
Then here you have for example your first hidden layer
I may have a second hidden layer a third hidden layer, and then finally my output layer. So how many layers does this network have?
[Audience]
How many how many columns can you count here?
5. Okay. Fantastic. How many?
Gaps between columns. Can you count?
4 only
Rotations you have. Okay, cool. All right, so we go from the first
Layer, which is also called a⁽¹⁾ we start the activation at the layer 1
We go to the activation at layer 2 and so on a⁽³⁾, a⁽⁴⁾
until the a capital L [a⁽ᴸ⁾] the last one so
We got from activation at layer 1 to activation layer 2 the W⁽¹⁾ matrix
basically
You go is lie with W⁽²⁾, W⁽³⁾ and so on right? So, how do you get that first? Neuron? Can you see anything?
So, okay. Let me see if I can make not too dark
Is the any better
Kind of okay, I whatever I go like this boom. Okay, anyone taking notes on paper?
[Audience: yes]
Sorry, okay
Yeah, whatever
After I turn on the light, okay. So how do you get the values for this guy here?
So this guy is gonna be the J's neuron on my what layer?
Second layer, right so aⱼ⁽²⁾ so this is gonna be my element-wise. Sorry, my non-linear function f
Where I have this W⁽ʲ⁾ which is the j's role of W(1) matrix, which is multiplied by X
So I have a row times a vector you get a scalar
Thank you and then plus bⱼ. What is bⱼ?
It's a scalar. Yes, that's correct.
Also called bias, right? Okay. What a choice of words. Sorry
and this is gonna basically be like the sum of the
scalar
Multiplications right? I mean the sum of the multiplications, and so how do you get these on? you get these guys, you multiply them by
the weights and then you get the first guy right and
Then for the second one
you try copy and paste doesn't work. So you to draw all those lines again!
[Audience: laugh]
And then you start realizing that you made a very bad decision
When drawing everything else. Okay. So where are these weights toward?
In w⁽¹⁾. Okay fantastic not gonna be fast forward you
know fast forward
Yeah, how pretty no this is PowerPoint ninja skills
Okay, I should be doing advertisements for and this should pay me
Microsoft
All right. So this is on your network, right? How pretty is it?
Thank you
[Audience: laugh]
Okay, I give you back the light here I
Should just turn on right everything I guess. I had let me know if we can turn off the first line of light
Okay, we had to figure that next time I guess. All right, so
We just use this representation where each of those layers you were observing before I'll just condense in one
Bold here. So in this case h is a vector, right?
And so a vector of whatever number of elements is just represented there in on the screen
And the same for the y. So here you had those matrices which are shooting the right directions the right right dimensionalities
And then here you had the non-linear functions
so you can think about my
ŷ here, This guy is
Some kind of ŷ function of my current input X, right?
So the X the pink guy it's feed into the network and then a network will give me a some kind of you know
I expect you to have this kind of output prediction
So this can be thought as a function that map's ℝⁿ to our C, where C is number of classes. That was capital K
But I guess I had to fix this right
so you can see these as mapping inputs to
final predictions
Usually it's better to think in a different way. So
What's happening is actually you met these ℝⁿ to some intermediate
Representation ℝᵈ and then you go finally to the final classification dimensions
where d the of the internal layer it's much much larger than the
Input and output dimensions. Why is that? because whenever you go in a very high dimensional space
Everything is far
Like really really really really really far apart
and so if things are very far
It's very easy to rotate
Stuff and get things to move a little bit then right if you go everything a very tiny little crumb space you try to move
things
Everything moves together right? But then if you go into this intermediate space where everything is so far apart
You can just kick things around. Okay, and it's much easier. So going to a higher
intermediate representation
dimensional intermediate representation, it's really really really
Helpful so
Potentially you can have a very fat Network right? You have an input very fat hidden layer. Just an output the cool part is that
if I have hundred neurons in my hidden layer, I
Can simply use 2 hidden layers of
10 neurons. There's going to be performing roughly the same. So instead of having this very very fat intermediate layer
I can just decide to stack a few hidden layers and the number of combination of those neurons, you know will
grow in exponentially
So it's, if you want a 1,000 layer want 1,000 neuron hidden layer you can just have 3
hidden layers of 10, right?
[Audience]
So in the second case where you have a cascade of things you will have data
Dependencies and you will have to wait for the guys
Down to have finish before starting the next operation. So by definition the more layers you stack the slower you get
on the other case you need to have so many many many more units in the other case in order to be able to
Go to actually be as good as you are by stacking just a few of those layers
So in other cases you will have to do many computations as well if you get parallel software
I guess like power parallel hardware, then you can prefer maybe those large
Versions, but I wouldn't go for those
[Audience]
Yeah, that's correct is bad so it takes also much more space in memory, all right so much time
We make noise
Okay, I can't watch my watch
Okay, never mind
All right, so, okay
So in this case my input lives in a 2 dimensional space
My hidden layer is going to be living a hundred dimensional space in my final class
my final output is going to be living in a 3 dimensional space and
This would be the second part where you start doing stuff with your computer, but we are in class we have no time
So a neural network training
Huh? How does it work? So we use this guy here the soft Arg max?
Which is a software version of the max of the art max, right?
Which is simply the fraction of the exponential divided by the sum of all the exponential of the other items, right?
We already seen this yesterday. Why do I write these stuff between zero and one?
Why it doesn't why didn't I use the square brackets?
[Audience]
So the answer was it's very unlikely I would say it's impossible why it's impossible?
Because the exponential function of the numerator is
Strictly positive, why doesn't reach one?
[Audience]
Because the exponential is strictly positive. That was the answer, correct
Yeah, the bottom doesn't is always going to be slightly larger than the numerator, right?
All right
So the input to be soft Arg max layer is called logit and the logits are the output the linear output of the network
Here we're gonna have our
Total loss the loss for the specific
for the old data set we have which is function of the Ŷ the prediction of the network for the whole set of
inputs and the vector C which is this vector of labels and
Which is gonna be simply here the average of this lower case and this curly, which is basically the per sample loss
Yann [Yann LeCun] uses capital L for that thing
so in this case, if I do if I want to do classification, my per sample loss is gonna be basically - log of
the
output of the
Soft Arg max at the correct class C. Okay, so
C is gonna be my correct class, which is that index one hot
Actually see was the the Cardinal or Deena no Cardinal number, right?
The blue y was the one hot encoding and my ŷ is gonna be the output of the network?
Which is the output of the soft arg max, so my per simple also gonna be the - log of that
Soft arg max are the correct
Case class right? So
Do you understand what I said? Yes, so just to test your understanding you're gonna be telling me what's right next
So let's say yeah, this loss is also called cross entropy or negative log-likelihood
So let's say my pink X which looks white
Is there and then I have my class the orange class equal to 1, therefore what's gonna be my blue y?
The one hot and coding of the class C
1 0 0 okay. Fantastic
alright, so let's say I feed these X to my
Neural net. So I'm going to compute these Y or case missing a white. Sorry, my bad. So here is a Y, right?
ŷ of this item here
So why do I write almost? No, sorry. Sorry. Sorry, my bad
So I put these X here inside this ŷ and the output of the network is gonna be this almost 1 almost 0 almost
0 what is almost 1?
[Audience]
Is it 1⁺ or 1⁻?
What is almost 0?
0 plus very good and what about the last one?
0 plus good. Alright, so if I have this guy here
What's going to be my percent per loss so my percent per loss is going to be
These output almost 1 almost 0 almost 0 and then class number 1. Ok. So what do I get here?
So here you're going to be computing the what is ŷ of C
ŷ of C is gonna be
Hold on yes. So ŷ of C is gonna be almost 1 which is 1⁻
okay, then you have log of 1-
[Audience]
So it's gonna be
0⁻ then it is a minus in front
You get 0⁺, this correct very good. How about so basically if you
input these X in my network the class I expect to have for that input is 1 and my network says
1 0 0
the loss is gonna be which basically is the penalty for saying, you know say bullshit is gonna be
oh, no penalty you're
Doing well. Ok. So let's see what's happening instead if my network says oh no. No, this simple is 0 1 0?
So my percent per loss of 0 1 0 & 1 is going to be what so what is ŷ of C?
Almost 0, what kind of Almost 0?
0+, what is log of 0+?
Negative infinity what is with a minus in front?
So this guy approaches +∞, right?
So that's why there is a plus there if you just write ∞ that's wrong for me. Okay?
+∞, -∞, ∞ are three different
items, different anymore
Okay makes sense
So if your networks say bullshit, you're gonna say +∞, very bad Network if the network says uh
Kind of right answer. You just say. All right, you're doing well. Yeah question
[Audience]
Second sorry
So ŷ
the question you cannot see maybe here in if you squint a little bit in gray you have ŷ is going to be a
function of your input X
Through two rotations and two squashings one squashing being the positive part and the other squashing being the soft arg max
Right. And so if you use these per sample loss on the on top of your soft Arg max then you get
This kind of cross entropy term and then if you compute what's written here you get basically this
If you input an x and your network is correct. You say good network good boy
If you stab your network say it's bullshit. Then you're gonna say bad, you know bad network order
makes sense
[Audience]
So ŷ is a vector and
I choose the seized items
So that you can see you can think about this one is ŷ?
Subscript C
But C is actually the yeah C is gonna be 1, 2 or 3, right?
So it's gonna be basically ŷ(1) or ŷ(2), ŷ(3). So one of the 3 items elements of ŷ
Makes sense. No. Yes, you can say no
Did I answer your question? no
So ŷ it's a vector of 3 items, 3 elements
[Audience]
Yeah here right ŷ if you squint a little bit it's gonna be the output of the network
Okay K classes yeah
And the output guy
So this inside this guy here inside is gonna be the logit to the linear output
And then you apply this G which is gonna be this soft arg max
Okay, which is kind of normalizing the outputs to be within 0 and 1 such that the sum of all the items of the output
Is going to be up to 1
[Audience]
So
Why don't you use it?
Mean square error, I think young yesterday addressed. Is this question?
He he actually wrote and wrote and written here's and written on the on the notebook. Right? So but the point is that this is
The loss function that we use for classification which gives you something that actually works
Other losses may not be optimal
So when you like to do classification we use this cross entropy, which also has other statistical property
I'm not going to be talking about here
all right, so since I'd like also to go over the
Notebooks and stuff. I will try to speed up a little bit
Alright so training how does training work?
So I just get all the parameters all the matrices like weight matrices biases and whatever I get a set of those
Weights and I called them Θ is gonna be in the collection of the set of all my trainable parameters
Such that I can write now my J of Θ
which is defined as the
loss
So it's the same stuff. Why did I change notation?
So what can you notice here what's inside this function this function is function of the
Parameters where is this function here. The loss is usually function of the
output of the network, right?
This ŷ is the output of the network. in this case since its capital is for the whole batch
Right. So this is the one the way we use the right when we can be right like the loss the type of loss is
You simply say or J is going to be my objective function for a optimization problem. We're gonna see it right now
So how does it work we can think about J being this purple guy here which looks like that
There I use like a lowercase
A lowercase θ which is basically a scalar you just think about having one parameter. And so if I have J on the
Y-axis, I'm gonna have θ on the x-axis, right? So how do you train these networks?
Usually you start with you know, a randomly initialized Network, which means you know
you pick just an initial θ₀ value that specific point you can see that the
The J which is gonna be called training loss
Has a specific value which is going to be my J at point θ₀.
There you can compute the derivative which you can't even see. It's a green line. They're
Parallel to the yeah, you can't see I know
Sorry again
Right how pretty so you had the green slope there which is showing you the derivative at that point
and then that is basically the derivative for my J function with respect to the parameter theta computed at the point θ₀.
Now the only thing you have to do is going to be taking a step
Towards left, so is that variable to be positive or negative?
So do you agree that the relative is
positive fantastic, but I'm taking a step towards the left and
so
how do you do that?
is actually you just put on -
Okay. Fantastic
So this is called how it's called these stuff here? okay
So this is gradient descent, right, how do you train on your own network?
In this
Okay votes. I heard another word here, who say back propagation here today?
No, I mean did I okay I did if I didn't mention back propagation yet, right. So, how do we train a network?
Gradient method right? Okay, cool
How to publish gradients how do you compute these gradients? So what is this the J in the W(y)
So this guy is gonna be my J in the Y
which is the partial with respect to the output times the Y in ∂W right and
similarly how this what is the partial derivative of the what is the
Jacobian of my target my objective function with respect to the Wₕ is gonna be my
partial derivative of the output of the cost with respect to the output of the network then times the Jacobian of the
The output of the network so with respect to the hidden layer
And then finally the partial of the hidden with respect to ∂W right? How is called this?
Back propagation. Okay. All right. So what is back propagation?
There are two computations, right, how do we train the network?
Okay, if you get it wrong on the midterm when I fail you
All right, yes
[Audience]
This the left is an exercise why these are plus here, okay. So in the last how many minutes I have
Five minutes really
Nine minutes, so that's a lot of time
So we're gonna go through
two notebooks
Maybe, terminal
cd work github pytorch
Conda activate
Mini course. Yeah works
Jupiter notebook
Okay, how do I share my screen system preferences yeah, but I cannot see
Arrangement mirror, okay
You can see no
So we're gonna be going through the spider classification right now
You
[Unclear]
thank you
So since he's gonna be oh you can see I stuff. I don't have to turn off the light
Okay, so here I'm gonna do basically
import random shit random stuff
Torch Torch and an optim, math, ipython such that you can see something I use my awesome default
Configuration. We have a device. What's the device used for?
For whatever the device you want to run the stuff only want so if this is taking care
Here, I just put the same number
So you see have seen before you should be able to understand this stuff and do it yourself
That's part of I think kind of the homework next year. We had to do this as homework remember
All right, so I just visualize the data you're ready seen this stuff, okay, so oh there is no surprise
So this is a starting point points are having two coordinates
Like each point has X and Y and then you have a color for the different class. I'm not running it too fast, right?
I'm not support. You're not supposed to read the code now
You read the code later and play with a notebook at least one hour right now
We just go through the notebook just to see that actually runs because you never know. It's an open source project
Right so linear model I'm gonna be training this guy over here, so I create a sequential which is a container
I don't have to use it, but it's easier and I put there to linear. What is linear? It's wrong, What's a linear?
It's on affine transformation. What's an affine transformation? five things
are gonna be on the midterm so, you know just realize
I going from D to H, where D is actually the input space H is gonna be the hidden and then from hidden on the output
Just linear layers, right? So, how are the decision boundaries here?
Crappy yes, correct linear, so I start this guy trains in a blast and then I show you the output
Nothing right, bad network
Its best right. So why are these decision boundaries put in this configuration? why they are not
rotated?
Why do you have the yellow area on the left-hand side and not on the other side
It tries to do it best right, so my accuracy it's 0.5 you can see.
so what is 0.5?
Ok who said random?
Okay, very good
All right. Otherwise you want to refresh your probability
Hmm. Okay 1/3, right?
Okay, you have no time but I wanted to add one more thing
Yeah, we don't have training losses here
what is the first value of the training loss?
The first this is the latest value I get right. So this is my final loss all
0.86, What is the first value of my loss?
Any idea
You see my screen here damn I cannot even okay
Ok figure out how much?
The first number you get there is no
why, you figure out if you don't figure out the next week
I tell you but you should figure it out right so you should try to use your brain, too
sometimes
Alright, so let's do something here. I'm gonna be adding this positive part in the center
Ok, so I just add one more little tiny
Zero the negative numbers, right? Everything else is the same. I don't change anything, but I
delete negative number spike with the Zook the thing either. I don't know the English name
Accuracy Oh No, okay
See are you excited are you waiting it for it kind of you are sleeping, I guess nice. Oh
Okay, cool, so
Yeah, two minutes left try changing the number of hidden layers, right so the try changing the sorry try changing the
dimension of the hidden layer
What does it happen?
if you use
2 hidden, 2 neurons in the hidden layer of five neurons
Sorry, try playing with this right and figure out what's happening
You can comment on Piazza you can start talking you can have like, you know
Conversations - all right, we really highly encourage you to
Play with these notebooks and figure out things in the last 30 seconds we go through another notebook
Which is gonna be exactly the same
Okay, but in this case my point look like this
You see anything?
kind of right so you see like this kind of banana, which is not a banana is like a
You know double like see Nike. Nike symbol. Alright, so I'm gonna be training here my linear network.
I train everything
Okay, I explained now don't worry, alright, so I trained my linear network, what is my linear network the same stuff as before.
I have sequential a container where I put my tool
What are those?
affine transformations. Yes, correct. I sent to the device. Oh
Okay, how do we train a network right?
So to train a network you have your input X. These are all my points
I feed them to the network inside my mother
And my mother will give me my y_pred right, and the definition of the model. It's this one is this container here? Okay, so
We have the model we feed we call the whole X you get y_pred
Then I compute the loss which is gonna be my criterion
to which is computed over my predictions and wise, the wise are the classes right and the y prediction are those
output of the network
In this case the criterion it's written here is going to be our MSELoss()
So we change before we were using actually a cross entropy
- log of the softmax, soft arg max
Now we are going to using a MSE because we are using a regression in a very no regression problem
So we compute the loss which is the quadratic distance between your output and the target, right?
So if you talk about the regression we talked about target if we talk about classification, we're gonna be talking about classes in labels
so labels
classification
regression we talk about
Target, okay. All right
So we compute the loss here and then I had to clean up whatever happened before so I say to my optimizer
Clean all the previous left over from the previous operation, which is this zero grad pass
Then I perform backward. What is backward what is back propagation?
Computation of the partial derivative of the
Second
Partial derivative of
loss with respect to the
Parameter, so lost not backwards is simply chain rule and computes all the partial derivative of your final loss which is gonna be in this
Case the mean squared error with respect to each and every parameter of your model, finally you do a step which is gonna be stepping
If you that's the gradient you step backwards in the direction of the gradient, okay?
All right, so we train this network, which didn't have a non linearity and it did something
I don't know how to interpret this loss and this
Is gonna be my output of the network? What is it?
linear regression
okay boring. Okay. So now I'm gonna do deep networks super exciting things. What do I change?
AAA
Just put, I just delete negative values, okay
How cool is that? All right, so I remove the negative values sometimes here real
Oh all sometimes I just use a hyperbolic tangent. I just split in two times so you can see the comparison
I train this stuff
and
See, let's see the prediction before actually training. So before training you're gonna get this kind of predictions
Right
Kind of shooting towards zero. I know for example line and the
Green Line is maybe representing the variance
Here where my cursor is is 0 so the variance here is like 0.2 roughly between all those predictions
Let's go down and let's watch how the network changed their final
output given that we have used the loss right and we have
We've moved against so we are in the mountain there is fog you can't see where the valley is
it's just walk towards the
slippery, you know what that thing that goes down right towards the
down to the body so after doing this procedure several times
Are you excited to see how this network perform?
I don't hear you. Okay. Thank you. Alright, so
Here
So guess which one? Okay guess which one is using the positive part and which one is using the hyperbolic tangent?
Okay, because you're solid Piper's damn
Okay, so left inside you can see how my network approximates my input is a what is that thing called
Can you see anything maybe you can see how does this stuff look like?
This looked like a straight line, right so my network
it's simply a
Output is simply a piecewise
linear
You know approximation of your input. This is because I just deleted the negative things
instead if you use the
What is it?
Like parabolic tangent. Yes
You get this guy here how smooth right?
Okay, why did I do this stuff? This is nicer right? I think
Okay, first of all, you can see the yellow thing which is the standard deviation
Which looks like fucked up here and less fucked up on the left hand side right see with the standard deviation is really spiky
so if you train an ensemble of network, these networks will kind of not agree as
Consistently as those other dudes on the left hand side moreover. Let me change one line. Let's put here number four
so I'm gonna be now looking at
Outside my training region data. Okay, I'm gonna be looking what's happening on the left and right
What do you expect to see? What do you expect these networks to do when you actually
Test the network
outside the training region
[Audience]
Okay, good intuition something similar
so this network will not work, right because network will only be able to
Generalize over data that is in a similar range if you ask your network that has been trained on this data
how to
interpret things that are over here?
they will say I don't know and
Unfortunately, the main issue is these are regression networks, so they will not tell you how confident
They are right, they are absolutely
I shouldn't say that word
Alright, whatever I said they won't tell you how confident they are, right. We are just telling you
Whatever that number but let's see. What's happening now
So what's going on here now, I just show you a little bit more right, on the side
The yellow one is going to be the standard deviation
and the green one is the variance you can see on the left hand side is the
ReLU
the rec linearly, the positive part function
Keeps having the final branches keeping they keep the same slope
whereas the one train with the hyperbolic tangent
It will saturate eventually. Okay, and so
You have to know this network will have side effects the choice of nonlinear function will have a side effect
Especially if you go outside the training domain region
Luckily you can use this technique
the n symbol variance prediction or estimation in order to estimate somehow the
uncertainty with which the prediction is made
This is really really really really important in terms of research, right? Sure
if you have your network that does regression you have no whatsoever clue about its own confidence if you train a
Bunch of networks that have different initial values you train them all with the same procedure
you can compute the variance in order to estimate the
Uncertainty with which a given prediction is made
with this
That was it for today. Thank you for listening and I see you now week, bye-bye
Questions
Okay other questions, hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Wait, wait, wait a sec. First of all, okay the sky bursts and whatever
They have to pay attention to what he writes
We have always the notes coming up on the website by Sunday
Such that you can revise the content before class if you come to class without revising content
You may not be fully, you know
Perceptive for whatever we talk about
That was it I think, all right. Thank you